hello and welcome to the 21st tutorial
on how to program in g-script 2. so
let's add
client died and let's do function on
player chats
I set a function on timeout so assemble
to go to and remember on timeout can
also is a special function that can also
be called with timer
oops
that can also be called with set timer
and how many seconds it takes before it
goes back to the beginning so here's a
new thing if
key down
a number
and brackets key down is a check and
that is used in if statements to see if
whatever key is down then something's
going to happen that's in these brackets
zero all num all these numbers stand for
a specific key
zero stands for the up Arrow key one
stands for the left Arrow key two stands
for the down arrow key three stands for
the red arrow key four is s five is a
six is
d 7 is M eight is tab
9 is
q and
10 is p
okay
we're not going to use anything past
three since we only want to use the
arrow keys
let's add zero so if I'm pressing the
top Arrow key it's going to run
whatever's in these parentheses
I wanna
mention that not key down does not work
with all the keys on the keyboard only
these specific 11 keys
now if you want to use whatever key you
want such as maybe Z or maybe J then
there's a different way to do that oh I
put a semicolon here there's a different
way to do that
with a function and I'm not going to get
into that in this tutorial
so let's make it so that if you press
the top Arrow key it's going to move us
up one tile
player y equals player dot y minus one
and let's add
let's copy this and place paste it three
other times
and change all the keys to the left
Arrow key to the bottom and to the right
and let's change it so it moves in
different moves Us in different
directions based on which key we press
if we press the left one it'll move us
minus one to the left if we press two it
moves one down if we miss press three
it'll move this one to the right
you can guess what this does this is a
admin boot script admin boots are things
that people call that allow you to move
through walls and move around quickly
around a server usually they're usually
they're only given to admins to
get to places quickly because it'd be
kind of easy to do stuff if you're a
player and you were able to walk through
anything and move very quickly then
let's add a way to exit this let's do if
player.chat is equal to
stop
then what's going to happen is
it's gonna we're gonna make it return
is a command that stops the function and
tracks and nothing happens it's going to
stop it's going to stop this Loop and
then we're not going to be able to to
run any of these things which means
we're not going to be able to run
quickly or through things anymore okay
let's press apply
and there's some bushes here
let's type boots
and you can see that we're running
faster than before and we are able to
run through them
because
we simply just move our x coordinate
through them or our y coordinate every
time we press the arrow key
we can also make us make ourselves run
faster we can change this to five
five
and let's type boots
and look how fast we're running now
we're pretty much running through
everything
we don't we don't even touch the bushes
now
let's type stop now stop
we're running normally again
so
that's it for this tutorial and I hope
you understand what return means and
what key down means and how you can use
them
anyway bye